https://www.tyrrells.com.au/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
Privacy Statement
Tyrrell’s Vineyards Pty Limited, ABN 52 000 114 527, and its related entities is covered by the National Privacy Principles as set out in the Privacy Act 1988 (and amended by the Privacy Amendment (Private Sector) Act 2000).
To comply with our obligations we have adopted a Privacy Policy which sets out how we manage privacy in our organisation.
As responsible corporate citizens we appreciate the importance of confidentiality. This part of the obligation remains unchanged by this privacy policy. The privacy policy deals with your additional right to privacy and is independent of our contractual and ethical obligations.
Definitions
• Tyrrell’s: Tyrrell’s Vineyards Pty Limited and subsidiary and associated companies.
Privacy Policy
>Definitions
>Purpose of the Policy
>The personal information that Tyrrell’s Vineyards collects
>Why we collect it
>Sources of information
>Overseas
>Access to your personal information
Purpose of the Policy
Tyrrell’s is covered by the Privacy Act and is taking all reasonable steps to comply with the Act and protect the privacy of the personal information that we hold. The Policy applies to Tyrrell’s and all its related entities.
The personal information that Tyrrell’s collects
Tyrrell’s collects the following personal information in relation to the individuals it deals with directly as customers and/or suppliers, or the individuals it deals with who are a contact person in customer and/or supplier organisations:
• your name;
• date of birth (customers only, where it is necessary to ensure that we adhere to the Liquor Act in relation to the sale/supply of liquor to minors);
• address and other contact details (telephone, facsimile, email, etc.);
• credit reference and associated information for a customer if they ask for an account to be opened;
• credit card details for charging for goods or services supplied by us; and
• bank account details for the payment for supplies or services received by us.
Video cameras are located at some of our sites for the purpose of security, and where installed, are normally operating all of the time. However, nothing is being recorded on film during the normal business hours of those sites. Films are only used outside normal business hours and these are over-written within two days unless there has been a breach of security and we believe the film needs to be retained and given to a law enforcement agency or equivalent body.
Why We Collect It
Tyrrell’s collects this information to enable us to manufacture and distribute wine and provide related services. This also includes the following purposes:
• selling you our product;
• selling you our services (winemaking, quality analysis, vineyard management, and other miscellaneous professional or consultative services);
• satisfying the service and delivery requirements of customers;
• contacting customers in relation to special product offerings, pricing changes, or legislative changes that may affect our service; and
• administering and managing the accounts payable and accounts receivable functions for the company.
Tyrrell’s may disclose this information to:
• our insurer/s;
• mailing houses, for use with our company’s mailings only;
• legal and other professional advisers; and
• government departments, but only when we are legally obliged to provide such information.
Sources of information
Where possible we will collect the information directly from our suppliers and/or customers. If personal information is collected from another party other than the individual themselves, then Tyrrell’s will take reasonable steps to inform that individual of the collection.
Overseas
Tyrrell’s does not send personal information overseas without the permission of the appropriate individual.
Access to your personal information
Tyrrell’s provides access to you in relation to the personal information that we hold about you. All requests for access will be:
• treated seriously;
• dealt with promptly;
• dealt with in a confidential manner; and
• will not affect your existing obligations or affect the commercial arrangements between you and Tyrrell’s.
We will provide access by allowing you to inspect, take notes of or receive copies or print outs of the personal information that we hold about you. Access will only be denied if:
• the request does not relate to the personal information of the person making the request;
• providing access would pose a serious and imminent threat to life or health of a person;
• providing access would create an unreasonable impact on the privacy of others;
• the request is frivolous and vexatious;
• the request relates to existing or anticipated legal proceedings;
• providing access would prejudice negotiations with the individual making the request;
• access would be unlawful;
• denial of access is authorised or required by law;
• access would prejudice law enforcement activities; or
• access discloses a ‘commercially sensitive’ decision making process or information; or
• any other reason that is provided for in the National Privacy Principles (NPPs) set-out under the Privacy Act.
We will take all reasonable steps to provide access within 30 days of your request. In cases where the request is not complicated or does not require access to a large volume of information, we will provide information within 14 days. A charge may be imposed if the time taken to retrieve archived information is considerable but this will be quoted and agreed prior to the work being done.
You can request access by calling or writing to the Financial Controller for Tyrrell’s.
Storage
We will take all reasonable steps to protect the security of the personal information that we hold. This includes appropriate measures to protect electronic materials and materials stored and generated in hard copy.
Legal reasons why we collect the personal information
Some of the information is collected in order to comply with our legal obligations in relation to the Liquor Act and taxation legislation.
What happens if you choose not to provide the information
You are not obliged to give us your personal information. However, if you choose not to provide Tyrrell’s with the requested information, we may not be able to provide you with the full range of our services.
Complaints
If you have any complaints about our privacy practices or wish to make a complaint about how your personal information is managed please contact the Financial Controller for Tyrrell’s. All complaints will:
• be treated seriously;
• be dealt with within 28 days;
• be dealt with in a confidential manner;
• be logged on a database/complaints register; and
• not effect your existing obligations or the commercial arrangements that exist between this organisation and you.
If you have provided us with personal information you have a right to make a complaint, have it investigated and dealt with under this policy.
Complaints can include matters such as:
• how personal information is collected;
• how personal information is stored;
• how this information is used or disclosed; or
• how access is provided.
You may complain orally or in writing, and once the complaint has been made, it will then be resolved in a number of ways:
1. Request further information and investigation: We may request further information from you. You should be prepared to give as many details as possible including details of any relevant dates and documentation. This will enable us to investigate the complaint and determine an appropriate and useful solution. All details provided will be kept confidential.
2. Discuss options: We will discuss options for resolution and if you have suggestions about how the matter might be resolved you should discuss these with us. We may also suggest other solutions or give examples of how the personal information can be revised or stored in a different way.
3. Refer to the CEO: If your complaint is not resolved to your satisfaction, it will be referred to the CEO. The CEO would be provided with the history and may discuss the complaint with the employees, or other parties that are involved.
4. Resolution: You will be informed of the outcome and the reasons for the decision. If this does not resolve the complaint, the matter will be referred to a mutually agreed intermediary.
5. If after the above steps have been followed you are still dissatisfied with the outcome you may refer the complaint to the Federal Office of the Privacy Commissioner.
Tyrrell’s is unable to deal with anonymous complaints as we are unable to investigate properly and follow-up such complaints. However, in the event that an anonymous complaint is received we will note the issues raised and try and resolve them appropriately. For example, we may wish to conduct further training or provide assistance in a given area.
Changes to the Privacy Policy
Tyrrell’s may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time by posting the amended version on our website at www.tyrrells.com.au
Information
For any further information about this policy please contact the Financial Controller for the company.
Address: Broke Road, Pokolbin NSW 2320
Phone: 02 4993 7000
Facsimile: 02 4998 7723
Sales 02 4993 7000
Tastings(02) 4993 7028
Emailtyrrells.wines@tyrrells.com.au
© Copyright 2020 Tyrrell’s Wines. All rights reserved | Privacy Policy
Liquor Licensing Act 2007. It is against the law to sell or supply alcohol to, or to obtain alcohol on behalf of, a person under the age of 18 years. Licence Number: 356529
ENJOY TYRRELL'S WINES RESPONSIBLY
Login
Remember me
Log in
Forgot your password?
Lost your password? Please enter your email address. You will receive mail with link to set new password.
Back to login
close
